Guide to the Dr. Milton R. Kramer papers, 1916-1946 MS0983.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Dr. Milton R. Kramer papers
1916-1946
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Kramer, Milton R.
MS0983.UA
1 Linear Feet
Materials in this collection include Milton Kramer's diplomas from high school and The George Washington University, certificates, books, and his medical bag (without instruments). They range in date from 1916-46.
Box 2
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
The provenance of this collection is not known, they were accessioned from an old backlog in 2001.
Biographical Note
Dr. Milton R. Kramer was a graduate of The George Washington University; A.B. 1931, M.D. 1934. He graduated from Alexander Hamilton High School, New York City, in 1926. While at GW he was a member of the Kappa Nu fraternity. After graduating medical school he practiced medicine in Kings Co., New York. During World War II he was a draft board physician from 1941-45, and received a Selective Service Medal from Congress in 1946.
N.B. This history note was written in 2005
Collection Scope and Content
Materials in this collection include Milton Kramer's diplomas from high school and The George Washington University, certificates, books, and his medical bag (without instruments). They range in date from 1916-46, and the provenance of this collection is not known, they were accessioned from an old backlog in 2001.
Bib#
8444390
Washington (D.C.); George Washington University. School of Medicine; George Washington University; Kramer, Milton R.
- Diploma - George Kramer, Elementary School, New York, NY, 06/30/1916 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Diploma - Sadie Kramer, Bay Ridge HS, New York, NY, 06/28/1918 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Diploma - Milton Kramer, Elementary School, New York, NY, 01/31/1932 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Diploma - Milton Kramer, Alexander Hamilton H.S., New York, NY, 06/30/1926 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Membership certificate for Alexander Hamilton H.S. League of "The Arista", 03/02/1926 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Membership certificate for Kappa Nu fraternity, 03/18/1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Diploma - Milton Kramer, B.A., GW, 06/10/1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Certificate - Kings Co., New York, certificate of Milton Kramer being on register of physicians and surgeons, 09/27/1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Selective Service appointment of Milton Kramer as draft board physician, 04/22/1941 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Certificate of appreciation to Milton Kramer for two years of service to the Selective Service, signed by FDR (facsimile), 1943 ca. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Certificate of appreciation to Milton Kramer for three years of service to the Selective Service, signed by FDR (facsimile), 1944 ca. (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Certificate of appreciation to Milton Kramer for four years of service to the Selective Service, signed by Truman (facsimile), 1945 ca. (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Certificate of Congress issuing Milton Kramer Selective Service Medal, signed by Truman (facsimile), 1946 ca. (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Medical bag (no instruments) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Office Gynecology, 4th ed., 1945 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Pictorial Handbook of Fracture Treatment, 2nd ed., 08/1947 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Anatomy of the Human Body, 22nd ed., 1930 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Prescription pad and address book, undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  General note
  Includes completed prescriptions for Dr. Kramer's patients.